



I've been tinkering with web technologies for more than 10 years, and I've only gotten more excited about it as time goes on. I'm passionate about finding simple solutions to complicated technical problems, and building the tools to satisfy those needs. I'm a strong believer of using the right tool for the job, and being uncompromising with regards to code quality.

Proficiencies

Client-side: HTML, JavaScript, CSS(3), SASS, LESS, Compass Server-side: Node.js, PHP, MySQL, Ruby(Rails), Java(Grails)

CMS: Adobe CQ, Sitecore, Wordpress

Education

The Illinois Institute of Art, Chicago - Chicago, IL

2005 - 2008

Bachelor of Fine Art in Web Design and Interactive Media w/ Honors

Work Experience

Critical Mass

March 2009 - Present

Developer

4th Year

- Led a team of 14 offshore developers as part of a full site redesign for a Fortune 100 insurance provider. This assignment was particularly challenging because the team was based in India, while I was in Chicago, and the client was in the Eastern Time zone. During this time, I developed my task management abilities, and my ability to delegate tasks efficiently.
- Built a social media hub for an automotive client. The page combined the data from all of their various social feeds, and I used them to display live statistics of the brands' social engagement. This assignment was an exercise in creating a "mash-up" using various social APIs, but was unique in it's display of the information gathered.

3rd Year

- Prototyped and built a highly interactive HTML5 video-driven microsite for a major car
 manufacturer. The site was the hub for online information requests and preorders for a brand
 new vehicle. The project was designed to work across all mobile devices as well, so optimizing
 HD video files to allow for performance across all devices and connection speeds was a major
 challenge that we met head on.
- Facilitated the migration of technical work for a major automotive client from an international
 office to our Chicago technology team. This process involved heavy documentation of the
 account's processes and best practices, along with hands-on training with developers within
 our office.

2nd Year

- Built a highly configurable usability prototype for a major airline's mileage rewards portal. This prototype was used across several rounds of usability testing, and was eventually leveraged in building out the final production site.
- Worked closely with the planning and creative disciplines to rapidly prototype and build various
 microsites for use in business pitches. This experience was particularly rewarding as we we're
 free to innovate with very little oversight, which lead to some extraordinary ideas and
 executions.



robertlaporte@gmail.com (847) 208 - 5449 www.robertlaporte.com

1st Year

- Built email templates to display across all email clients, using old markup practices for visual consistency.
- During this time I also helped to build and maintain various client microsites.

Tribal DDB

January 2009 - March 2009

Flash/Web Developer

My role at Tribal was to perform multiple tasks within the technology discipline. The first major task was to rapidly prototype, and build, complex Flash ad units for site takeovers and regular ad distribution. The second was to maintain and extend an existing large-scale Flash application for a Fortune 100 brand. My largest contribution during this time was to refactor a portion of the application, allowing the homepage to be entirely XML driven. This enabled designers and content producers to quickly deploy content changes to the testing environments for client approval, without the need for technical changes.

- Developing complex user experiences in Flash/Actionscript
- Maintaining and refactoring pre-existing flash sites and applications
- Performing various web development and maintenance tasks

Market M

Fall 2008 - December 2008

Web Development Intern

My internship with Market M was my first introduction to client work within a team. The production team consisted of two designers, a copywriter, and myself as the developer. The role was to cut up the provided Photoshop documents, and create their HTML/CSS/JS counterparts. This role was certainly an eye opener as I spent many late nights accommodating the endless revisions our clients requested. This environment helped me to quickly realize the importance of a strong development foundation using programming patterns, for easy iterations and changes, rather than re-inventing the wheel each client request.

- Responsible for front-end and back-end technologies (PHP/MySQL).
- Designing HTML/CSS/JS templates of Photoshop mockups.
- Integrating Content Management and e-Commerce solutions